Guide to the Juan Felipe Herrera Papers, ca. 1970-1998 M1043
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 4: Manuscripts and Literary Works by Others
  - Red Trapeze Monopoem Magazine, SF, Ca. (JFH, editor, et al), last copies of issues, original paste-ups, typed submissions by various poets including Margaret Randall from Havana, 1979, Victor Martinez, Eduardo Langagne (Mexico City) and manymore. 50p.1981. San Francisco, Ca. Capp Street years. (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Ryan, Joaquin. Xeroxed (only copy) of Therefor War, manuscript of poetry by my son. 143 pages. 1989. (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Ryan, Joshua. Removable Souls. By JFH son. poet. Sykik Groove Spoken Word Studios. SF. 1996. 27 pp. (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Saenz, Benjamin Alire. Dark & Perfect Angels. Final draft. 1/8/93. 179 pp. (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Sagel, Jim. Virgin (story). 37p. w/ letters: 2/26/92, 4/17/91) 37 pp. (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Scherrer, Phoebe. Homespun Poems. Iowa City, 1989, edited by JFH. (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Scherrer, Phoebe. poet. Iowa. Poetry collection journal. 62 pp.and Iowa Register newspaper article: 1/7/90 - Hospital Stay Helps Launch Iowan's Poetry. (Box 52, Folder 13)
  - Soto, Gary. Nerdlandia. a play w/letter. 45p. 6/24/98. envelope. (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Joy Tlou's partial short story. African-American Iowa writer. 1992. (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Trejo, Ernesto. El dia entre las hojas. 83p. signed. w/flyer. 11/1/91.Fresno, Ca. (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Unicorn, San Francisco literary magazine, part of "Heirs" a collective that included Duran Garcia, Alejandro Murguia and Roberto Varagas.1971, 50 pp. (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Velez, Felipe Ulloa. That Corner of Time. Poems, folded sheet, San Francisco, CA, mid 1980s. (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Mariache Drag Star Project Video portfolio, 1995. Linda Villatore, producer/writer, 30 pp. (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - "Calacas Machetiras" Art Lit journal. 11/2/91. LA Calif. 10 pp. (Box 64, Folder 7)
- Series 5: Personal and Legal Papers, Miscellaneous Material
  - Subseries 1: Personal Papers
    - Certificate of Baptism, Cetificate of Birth, Notification of Birth Registration. Mother's handwriting on papers and envelopes. Social Security documents for mother Maria Luz Garcia and father, Felipe Emelio Herrera (1951-70's). (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Mother's Cremation Papers. Death Certificate. 8/12/86. (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - School Reports. 2nd grade, 6th grade, 9th grade (Commencement exercises). My mother's writing on envelopes and reports. (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Diplomas, Photos and Awards. High School. 1967. My mother's writing on envelope. (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Black and White Xerox of "Self-Portrait with Brownie" 1966. San Diego, CA (JFH) (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Periodical sheet. San Diego Evening Tribune. "Future Leaders -37 Get Grants to UCLA" 8/10/67. JFH included. (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - Xerox. Luna Magazine Cover with Mom's photo. Spring 98. (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - Roosevelt Memories; Junior High School Yearbook. San Diego, Ca. 1962. (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - Roosevelt Junior High School yearbook. San Diego, Ca. 1963. (Box 53, Folder 15)
    - Roosevelt Junior High School yearbook. San Diego, Ca. 1964. (Box 53, Folder 16)
    - San Diego High School Yearbook. 1967. 236 pages. signed. (Box 53, Folder 17)
    - Business Card File-Approximately 96 business cards (Box 53, Folder 18)
  - Subseries 2: Legal Papers
    - Notice of use assignment, 3/13/95 (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Pyle, Charles. Letters, 3/28/95, 4/13/95 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    - Pyle, Charles. Notification to temporarily stop distribution of Night Train to Tuxtla, (with complaint), 4/3/95 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Herrera, Juan F. Letters: 4/5/95, 4/19/95, 8/5/95. (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Wieland, Charles. Letter (and general denial), 4/5/95 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Pyle, Charles. Application to appear as counsel, pro hac vice, 4/13/95 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Stipulation to extend time, 4/17/95 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Fax: Memo of agreement 4/17/95 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Answer of defendant: University of Arizona Press 4/19/95 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - General Denial, 4/24/95 (3 copies) (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Receipts for certified mail, re: Romero v. Herrera (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - Amended notice of hearing, 5/22/95 (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - Proof of service on the State Bar of California, 5/26/95 (Box 54, Folder 13)
    - Hogue, Kristin G.: Correspondence, 6/7/95, 8/1/95 (Box 54, Folder 14)
    - Notice of case management conference, 7/12/95 (and case assignment)[also includes faxed copies of State of Arizona defense documents] (Box 54, Folder 15)
    - Armstrong,Michael. Letter confirmation of conformed Stipulation of Stay, 7/12/95 (Box 54, Folder 16)
    - Proof of service by mail, 7/12/95 (Box 54, Folder 17)
    - Armstrong, Michael. Letter regarding approval of stipulation, 7/17/95. (Box 54, Folder 18)
    - Cox, Stephen F. letter to JFH, 8/17/95 (Box 54, Folder 19)
    - San Diego Superior Court Notification, 8/18/95 (Box 54, Folder 20)
    - Case management conference questionnaire, 8/30/95 (Box 54, Folder 21)
    - Notice of dismissal by court, Romero vs. Herrera, 4/22/96 (Box 54, Folder 22)
    - Photocopies of University of Arizona Press file regarding publication of "Night Train to Tuxtla" [1 of 2] (Box 54, Folder 23)
    - Photocopies of University of Arizona Press file regarding publication of "Night Train to Tuxtla" [2 of 2] (Box 54, Folder 24)
    - "Night Train to Tuxtla" dust jacket. (Box 54, Folder 25)
    - Announcement for Alarcon defense coalition fundraiser, 10/1/84 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Alarcon defense coalition sign up sheet, 10/1/84, at Capp St. Center (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Alarcon's defense contribution list, recorded by Margarita Robles (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Defense Fund Contributors' List (to Margarita Robles) (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Alarcon's Defense Fund contributions: Alarcon's notes (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Notes for mailing list (Alarcon case) by Margarita Luna Robles (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Defense fund contributions to Alarcon's lawyer (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Francisco's Alarcon's hearing attendees (list) 10/2/84 (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Fundraising pledges for Francisco Alarcon Defense Fund (organized by Margarita Luna Robles) (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Letter of support for Francisco Alarcon: Union of Left Writers, signed by Jack Hirschman, 10/84 (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - "Poet Tries To Rebuild Life," S.J. Mercury News, 11/4/84 (Francisco Alarcon) [photocopied news article] (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - "Complaint for Damages and Injunctive Relief," Francisco Alarcon, plaintiff, 12/24/84 (Box 55, Folder 12)
    - Press conference announcement: "Francisco Alarcon's lawsuit against the city...," 3/18/85, El Tecolote newspaper office. (Box 55, Folder 13)
    - "Francisco Alarcon, Plaintiff vs. Cornelius Murphy, Chief of Police San Francisco.." 15 pages, April 1985. Xerox. (Box 55, Folder 14)
    - "Onda on the Red Jeep: A Memoir," by J F Herrrera, written shortly after Alarcon's arrest. (Box 55, Folder 15)
    - "Openly Gay Latino Poet radiates joy..." 4/8/90, S.F. Examiner/Chronicle (Box 55, Folder 16)
    - Recording Death: Theodore Gomez, 9/22/84 (Box 55, Folder 17)
    - Coroner's Report Theodore Gomez, 9/24/84 (Box 55, Folder 18)
    - Recording Death: Larry W. Gaines, 10/23/84 (Box 55, Folder 19)
    - Coroner's Report Larry W. Gaines, 10/24/84 (Box 55, Folder 20)
    - Opening statement notes of William Melvin White's attorney, Burt: by Margarita Luna Robles (Box 55, Folder 21)
    - Murder trial of T. Gomez: court proceedings - defendant, Melvin White, 10/23-24/84 [transcript of detectives' interview with murder suspect William Melvin White] (Box 55, Folder 22)
    - Murder trial of T. Gomez: court proceedings - witness, Ted Porter, 10/26/84 [transcript of detectives' interview with murder suspect Ted Porter] (Box 55, Folder 23)
    - Murder trial of T. Gomez:court proceedings - witness, David Murdock 11/18/84 [transcript of detectives' interview with murder suspect David Murdock] (Box 55, Folder 24)
    - Penalty Phase Trial Notes, by Margarita Luna Robles, to D.A. William Fazio, 6/12/91 approx. 80 pp. (Box 55, Folder 25)
    - Murder trial of Theodore Gomez:court proceedings - witness testimony, Francisco Alarcon 7/10/91 [transcript of trial testimony] (Box 55, Folder 26)
    - Photocopied news items regarding the homicide case of Tede Gomez, 1991-1992. (Box 55, Folder 27)
    - Ellen Gomez's note to Margarita Luna Robles regarding news items of murder trial of her son Ted [contains photcopies of news items; transcript of Oprah Winfrey Show episode, 12/30/91 with minor connection to murder case] (Box 55, Folder 28)
    - "Otra," xeroxed poem by Manuel Machado with note by Luis Gomez (deceased), father of Tede Gomez, slain in San Francisco. We visited the court hearings and become friends with. the family. 1995. (Box 55, Folder 29)
  - Subseries 3: Awards, Newspaper Articles, and Miscellaneous Material
    - American Book Award, 1987. Before Columbus Foundation. (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - BABRA Bay Area Reviewers Association Awards Nominee Certificate. 1995. (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - 1/3/98. 1997 FOCAL Award Winner Announcement. 4 pages. (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Certificado de Meritosolisimo a Captitan Juan Felipe Herrera. 12/17/97 CSU-Fresno. (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - NBA "Brief Description of Work Accomplished and Impact Statement. 1985 1 p. (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Union de Escritores, UNE: minutes of meetings, 1981-1982; letter from UNE secretary, poet Juan Cuellar (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - By-laws, Management outlines; Friends of the Mission Cultural Center, mid 1980s (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - Mission Possible. article by Stephen Kessler (on JFH), Santa Cruz Express, 2/2/84 (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - Partial newspaper article on El Teatro Campesino 20th Anniversary show in San Juan Bautista, 1985, featuring JFH. (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - Bay Guardian weekly newspaper. Vol.20.No. 35. Feature Cover: JFH poetry winner, with poetry supplement. 48 pp. 6/86 (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - New York Public Library Staff Newsletter feature on JFH, 2/27/97; Fresno Bee Article, 3/23/97; Certificate of Appreciation from the Festival de la Familia, 1997 (Box 56, Folder 11)
    - Publisher's weekly Xerox: "Poetry: A Risky Business." Laughing out Loud" book. 2 pages, 3/23/98 (Box 56, Folder 12)
    - Together/ Belmont Cluster/ Juntos: newsletter, JFH feature, Los Angeles, CA, 1998 (Box 56, Folder 13)
    - Articles on Chicano artist; writers: Yolanda Lopez, LA Times, 1978; "Chicano Writers can't crack prejudice of New York publishers," by Howard Taylor Jr., SF Examiner, 8/4/84 (Box 56, Folder 14)
    - Two reviews, Yolanda M. Lopez, artist at Latin American Film Festival, 1982 (Box 56, Folder 15)
    - Article on Margarita Luna Robles, 11/83. "Reading to the Beat." 1 page xerox. Metro Guide, San Jose, CA. (Box 56, Folder 16)
    - Article on Margarita Luna Robles, El. Observador. mid 80's. ip. (Box 56, Folder 17)
    - Harry Gamboa, Jr.; zeroxed articles and announcement. Ismania. 3/28/87. 40 pages. (Box 56, Folder 18)
    - Humanizarte, tabloid mailing list, San Francisco, CA, early 1980s (Box 56, Folder 19)
    - WORC'S Magazine 1992/ chicanos poets & more 40 pp. (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - Selena Tee-Shirt silk screen design for Manikrudo Workshop, 1995, by JFH (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - 1) East Bay Monthly Cover. 5/97. Painting from Calling the Doves, artist Elly Simmons. 2) "Defensive Tacos" Cartoon Paste-up by JFH 3) Article by Victor Martinez on LA BAMBA, early 80's. [put in OS Legal Box labeled "Misc"] (Box 64, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 4: Flyers, Announcements, and Similar Materials Regarding Herrera Works or Readings, and Works or Readings of Others
    - Poster for The Last Testament Book, published by Citybender Publishing, San Diego, CA, 1978 JFH editor (Box 56, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous poetry periodicals: Poetry Flash, September 1979; October 1980;Citybender, 5 issues late 1970s. (Box 56, Folder 21)
    - Citybender broadside, 1980 JFH editor in chief (Box 56, Folder 22)
    - Various notes, flyers, maps, contacts for the 1980 Chicano Moratorium Spiritul Walk, 1980 (Box 56, Folder 23)
    - Daily Collegian, CSU-Fresno, 12/2/82: JFH reading "From Fowler to El Salvador." (Box 56, Folder 24)
    - Flyer "Autumn Raza Writers' Reunion," 10/1/83 (Box 56, Folder 25)
    - "Troca Accompanies Poetty Readings," article in La Voz," student newspaper at CSU-Fresno, 1983. (Box 56, Folder 26)
    - Tickets for Mediammix shows: Raffle ticket, 6/29/84; Funky Household Blues, 4/18-19/86; Laughing Up the Street, 3/1/86 (Box 56, Folder 27)
    - Artist Call, 1984 (Box 56, Folder 28)
    - Mediammix, 3/1/86 (Box 56, Folder 29)
    - "Funky Household: Downhome Blues and Comedy Review" Program, 1986 (Box 56, Folder 30)
    - Intersection 4/12/86 (Box 56, Folder 31)
    - Gato's Journal, vol. 1 no. 1 March/April 1987; vol. 1, no.2 July/August 1987 (Box 56, Folder 32)
    - Flyer and notes for Facegames book party, 1/20/87 (Box 56, Folder 33)
    - American Book Award Ceremony Tabloid, 5/16/87, JFH feature (Box 56, Folder 34)
    - Revolution Skyscraper poetry and performance program 12/8/87 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Brochure for "The Bike," a film by Gary Soto, JFH, narrator, 1990 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Flyer for "I Didn't Start Out to be a Poet," San Jose, CA, 5/9/91 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - "Thirteen Fresnos," two announcements, 3/17/92 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - "The Man with the Cactus Heart," poetry reading 5/23/92 (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Flyer for "New Letters," radio interview with Rebeka Presson, 6/3/92 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - "Monsoon!" Bisbee, Arizona Poetry Festival, Aug. 7-9/ 1992 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Bumbershoot, September, 1992 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - University of Arizona Poetry Center, Fall 1992-Fall 1993 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - Writers Live at the Library, JFH at Flint Public Library, Flint, Michigan, 9/20/93, postcard announcement. (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - Announcements regarding poetry contest: Reflections from the Yard, 11/4/93 (Box 57, Folder 11)
    - I Don't Have to Show You No Stinking Badges, John Wright Theatre, CSU-Fresno, October 1994, JFH appearing as Buddy Villa (Box 57, Folder 12)
    - Bounders; Writing Multiculturalism. A Conference, New College of California 4/15-16/1994; Children's Book Press, Fall 1995 catalog (Box 57, Folder 13)
    - Currents from the Dancing River, Gonzalez, Ray ed., publishing announcement, Harvest Books, 1994 (Box 57, Folder 14)
    - CSU Summer Arts, July 3-30, 1995 (Box 57, Folder 15)
    - Stone Alleys, Poetry and Performance, MACLA, San Jose CA, 11/18/95 (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - Flyer for Chicano poetry book against Proposition 187, 1995 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Press release regarding JFH workshops at the Guadalupe Cultural Arts Center, San Antonio, TX, 1995 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Flyer: An Evening Honoring Jose Antonio Burciaga, 10/13/96 (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Flyer: Poetry presentation in NYC schools, 4/18/97 (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Flyer for "Celebrating Our Mothers' Spirits," Readings and Book Party, 11/97 (Box 58, Folder 6)
    - Flyer for 26th Annual National Association for Ethnic Studies Conference, 3/28/98 (Box 58, Folder 7)
    - Cultura Latina Bookstore newsletter, JFH mentioned, Spring 1998 (Box 58, Folder 8)
    - "The Leash," Teatro Gusto and Poetasumanos presentation, July, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous flyers and announcements of JFH works or readings, 1970s. (Box 58, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous flyers and announcements of JFH works or readings, 1980s [1] (Box 58, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous flyers and announcements of JFH works or readings, 1980s [2] (Box 58, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous flyers and announcements of JFH works or readings, 1990s [1]. (Box 58, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous flyers and announcements of JFH works or readings, 1990s [2] (Box 58, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous flyers and announcements of JFH works or readings, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Poster for "Soldado Razo," by Luis Valdez, presented by Grupo Fantasma, VI Festival de Teatro Universitario, Universidad Veracruzana, 1977 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Living Up the Street, book party invitation for Gary Soto, mid 1980s (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Invitation to Ya Vas Carnal, poetry by Rodrigo Reyes, Francisco X. Alarcon, and Juan Pablo Gutierrez, 6/5/85 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Bovine Interventions, University of Iowa Writers' Collective Broadside, vol 2 no 1, 1990. (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Poster for 1990 Ethnic Women Writers, San Jose State University, 1990 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Flyer for "Soldados," by Charley Trujillo, 3/29/91 (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Entre Americas: El Taller Nepantla, A MACLA and Villa Montalvo Collaboration, 10/1/-12/2/1995 (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - El Teatro de la Esperanza - When El Cucui Walks, 1/17/1995 CSU-Fresno (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - News article on Victor Martinez's NBA Award, 1/10/96; Postcard flyers for Culture Clash Show, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - Promotional Packet from Armando Cepeda: artists with color photos of work, 8/17/98 (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - De Las Otras/Do Los Otros, flyer, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous flyers and announcements about works and readings of others, 1970s. (Box 59, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous flyers and announcements about works and readings of others, 1980s. (Box 59, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous flyers and announcements about works and readings of others, 1990s. (Box 59, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous flyers and announcements about works and readings of others, n.d.. (Box 59, Folder 16)
    - Poetry reading handbill. Original lettering. 2/25/83. [put in OS Legal Box labeled "Misc"] (Box 64, Folder 11)
    - OBOE magazine. SF, Ca. 1983. JFH poems. 46 pp.[put in OS Legal Box labeled "Misc"] (Box 64, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 5: Literary Tabloids, Broadsides, Magazines, Posters, Announcements and Other Material
    - Folio 11: Tin Tan. Revista Cosmica. San Francisco: a) Number 3. 22 pp. Art & Lit. Spring 1976.; b) Number 4. summer-otoflo. Fall 1976. 22 pp.; c) Number 5. Verano 1977. 22 pp.; d) Number 6. Otono-Fall, 1977. 22 p. (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Folio 1: Various subjects: a) Yolanda M. Lopez / Works: 1975-178. MFA Brochure. l4p. La Jolla. Mandeville Art; b) ASCO "83. 5/ 18-6/ 12/83. UCSC. Exhibit. 6p.; c) One More Canto: A Night of Chicano Poesia y Musica at the Reno Club. Sacramento. 2/7/ 1978. RCAF. Chapbook of poems. Jose Antonio Burciaga, Bernice Zamora, Katarina Zamora, JFH, Jose Montoya, Javier Pacheco, Irma Range!, Francisco Santana. l4 pp.; d) Flyer for VOLCAN anthology party. 2/25/ 84; e) W'ORCs Aloud Allowed. Lit mag. San Antonio. 1990. edition. '40 pp. Produced by poet, Ralph La Charity; f) Artist Call: Against US Intervention in Central America. SF, Ca. 1984. 24 pp. silk-screen cover (Ralph Castro). Folio 2: Broadsides by JFH: g) Citybender. Literature and arts broadside. JFH (editor/ chief). San Diego, Ca. 1977-78. Vol.1. No.1. (Soto, Forché, Trejo, et a!.), Vol. 1. No. 2. Rodolfo Braceli feature. Vol. 2. No. 7. (Mujeres Muralistas de San Diego). Vol.2. No. 9. (Gustavo Segada / Alfredo Arreguin). h) Gato's Journal. JFH, ed. (Victor Hernandez Cruz). 7/85. Broadside. (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Folio 3: Various subjects: a) 17x22 dou-tone poster of Mission Street Manifesto. JFH (from Exiles of Desire, 1983). Designed by Cecilia Brunazzi. San Francisco, Ca. This poster was put up on storefronts and posts on Mission Street, between 16th and 24th as JFH recited the poems to the public at large; b) Dust jacket[?] pasteup of A Night in Tunisia, poetry collection by JFH and Margarita Luna Robles, 1985; c) Dust Jackets of Night Train to Tuxtla. 1994. (8 paperback, 8 for cloth edition.) (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Folio 4: Various Literary Tabloids [1 of 2]: a) Mala Vida. Cuernavaca, Mex. Aflo Ill. Num.13. 6/97. 26 pp.; b) El Andar. 11/96. vol.7. #5. Jose Antonio Burciaga Feature. 24 pp.; c) Soledad Star, prisoner publiocation 8/86. (JFH poem). 8pp.; d) Brigada Subersiva. No. 10. 5/93. Mexico DF. l6p.; e) The Threepenny Review (JFH memoir). 34 pp. Spring 1994. #57. [photocopy of memoir, issue held in micorform]; f) The American Poetry Review. Vol. 21. No. 8. 12/92. JFH poems.56 pp. [poems photocopied, issued held in microform]; g) The Collegian. 11/11/94. MLRobles front cover. 8 pp. CSU-Fresno; h) Clambake. CSU-Fresno. 3/10/95. Teatro feature (JFH class). 8 pp.;i) Poetry SF. 1986. #4. Chicano poetry Issue. l2 pp. SF, Ca.; j) Outlook. No. 41. 12/1994. Review JFH book. 38 pp. (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Folio 4: Various Literary Tabloids [2 of 2]: k) Tornado Alley. Vol.1. No.1. 12/91. JFH essay on writer's workshop. 26 pp.; l) Sunday Register. Iowa News. article on Phoebe Scherrer. (JFH worked with this poet). 6 pp. 1/7/90; m) San Antonio Inter-American Bookfair and literary Festival Tabloid. 10/90. 48 pp. (Aztlan Photo Album Memoir/ Circa. 1971. JFH). (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Folio 5: Humanizarte Tabloid. San Francisco: a) Vol. 7. No.1. Summer 1986. 7 pp. Tenaz Teatro Feature in Mexico.; b) Vol. 9. #1. Spring 1988. (editor, Victor Martinez). Cecilia Guidos, martivon Galindo, Lorna Dee Cervantes (Nora Astorga Feature). 8 pp. (Box 65, Folder 5)
    - Folio 6: El Suplemento Cultural: La Opinion. Los Angeles3/17/2003: a) Cultura Chicana: Los Angeles. Num. 11. 7/13/80. 16 pp. "Artistas Chicanos en Los Angeles."; b) Deaffo a La Piramide: Nueva Poesia Chicana. Num. 38. 4/19/81. l6p. (eds. JFH & Francisco X. Alarcon.). [graphic design: JFH]. (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Folio 7: Various Tabloids. Bay Area: a) Haight Ashbury Literary Journal. Vol.3. No. 1. (Juan Alicia & Margarita Luna Robles feature.). l6 pp. 1987. SF; b)Matrix. 9/84. 12 pp. womens poetry. Santa Cruz, Ca.; c) Matrix. 11/85. l2 pp. Chicana visual artists. Santa Cruz, Ca. (Box 65, Folder 7)
    - Folio 8: Chicano poetry issues in Mexico: a) La Semana de Bellas Artes. INBA. 6/18/80. (eds. JFH, Francisco X. Alarcon). Chicano poetry and Literature. l6 pp. Mexico City; b) El Gallo illustrado. 4/11/82. Nueva Narrativa Chicana. 24 pp. (Box 65, Folder 8)
    - Folio 9: San Jose Mercury News Feature: Arts & Book section. 3/12/98. "A Special Fury: Latino Writers." (JFH, MLRobles, Burciaga, Candelaria, et a!.) 32 pp. (Box 65, Folder 9)
    - Folio 10: Poetry Flash / Berkeley: a) No. 179. 2/88. (JFH feature). l6 pp.; b) No. 184. 7/88. (JFH / "Cuatro Cabrones"). l6 pp.; c) No. 259. 3/95. (JFH) "The Joker's Passport." 40 pp. (Box 65, Folder 10)
    - Folio 12: El Tecolote Literario (JFH, Francisco X. Alarcon, et al eds.). San Francisco. [1 of 2]: a) Vol. No. 1. 1980. l2 pp.; b) Vol. 1. No. 4. 1980? l2 pp.; c) Vol. 2. No. 1. 3/81. 8 pp (Julio Cortazar interview); d) Vol. 2. No. 2. 7.81. l2 pp.; e) Vol. 2. No. 3-4. 12/81. TENAZ feature. 14 pp.; f) Vol. 3. No. 1. 3/82. l2 pp.; g) Vol.3. No. 2. 1982. 12 pp.; h) Vol. 3. No. 3. 12/82. 8 pp.; i) Vol.4. No. 1. 1983. 8 pp. (Box 65, Folder 11)
    - Folio 12: El Tecolote Literario (JFH, Francisco X. Alarcon, et al eds.). San Francisco. [2 of 2]: j) Vol. 4. No. 2. 1983. l2 pp. (Harry Gamboa Jr. feature); k) Vol.4. No. 3. 1983. 12 pp.; l) Vol. 5. No. 2. 1984? 8 pp.; m) Vol. 6. No. 1. 12/85. l6 pp. (Box 65, Folder 12)
- Series 6: Photographs and Slides
  - Subseries 1: United States
    - 29 b/w prints of RCAF murals in Sacramento. Ca. 1970-73. RCAF photographer? (Box 59, Folder 17)
    - 18 b/ w prints of installation of Chicano Park Murals, San Diego, Ca. Royal Chicano Air Force group from Sacramento, Ca. 1973. 1 print of Centro Cultural de Raza -- Toltecas en Aztlan, Balboa Park, San Diego. Ca. by Memo Cavada [RCAF photographer?] (Box 59, Folder 18)
    - Camera-Ready half-tone of artwork by Jose Antonio Burciaga (Alurista sketch, 1976) (Box 59, Folder 19)